Muhammad Hassan Raza,

Mobile: 00393427054564 E-mail: hassan_raza_khan@live.com

Skype: hassan98605

MUHAMMAD HASSAN RAZA KHAN

OBJECTIVE:

Seeking a challenging position in prestigious company where education, professional training, experience and commitment to excellence will be utilized to solve telecom and computer networks and telecommunication related problems. Technical and business-savvy professional with a pioneering 4+ year career reflecting strong qualifications, coupled with Service Provider multi-vendor experience & a well-rounded master education with expert level certification of Cisco Networks .Possessing extensive experience in IP Data Network Planning.

EDUCATION:

2012-2013	Masters in Computer Network Engineering (CGPA accumulative B+)			
2004 - 2008	HALMSTAD UNIVERSITY, Halmstad Sweden.			
	Bachelors in Electrical (Telecommunication) Engineering (CGPA 2.4)			
2001 - 2003	COMSATS Institute of Information Technology, Lahore			
	 F.Sc [Pre - Engineering] (754/1100 1st division) 			
1999 - 2001	P.A.F Intermediate College Lahore cantt.			
	Matriculation (Physics, Chemistry, Computer) (565/850 1st division)			
	P.A.F Intermediate College Lahore cantt.			

COURSES/CERTIFICATIONS:

• CCNP TSHOOT Troubleshooting of computer networks (Version 6.0)

Troubleshoot IPv4 addressing services

- · Troubleshoot IPv6 routing issues
- Troubleshoot network infrastructure services
- · Troubleshoot network performance issues on switches and routers
- · Troubleshoot network integration issues affecting wireless connectivity, VoIP, and video

· Practice maintenance procedures and fault resolution in a secure infrastructure

Institute: Halmstad University Sweden.

CCNP SWITCH Implementing IP Switching (Version 6.0)

- Implement, monitor, and maintain switching in an enterprise campus network
 - Implement appropriate spanning tree protocols in campus networks
 - Implement VLANs in campus networks
 - Configure and optimize high availability and redundancy on switches
 - Describe and implement LAN security features
 - Plan and prepare for advanced services in a campus infrastructure

Institute: Halmstad University Sweden.

CCNP ROUTE Implementing IP Routing(Version 6.0)

• Explain complex network requirements and design models for implementing advanced

routing service in an enterprise network

- Implement EIGRP and OSPF in an enterprise network
- Exchange routing information between interior gateway protocols
- Implement various mechanisms for controlling routing updates and traffic
- Implement BGP to allow an enterprise network to connect to an ISP
- Describe a basic implementation for branch office and mobile worker connectivity
 - Implement IPv6 in an enterprise network

Institute: Halmstad University Sweden.

Training of Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)

Version: 840-12

Institute: CORVIT Systems, Lahore

HAUWEI BTS & BSC Software Configuration and Hardware Implementation

Institute: U.E.T, Lahore

EXPERIENCE:

University Delgi Padua Italy (Researcher network Secuirty) from Jan 2016

- Working In CCN and NDN Security measures.
- Working on secure mobility for Name data networks research project of Cisco.
- Doing Research on Pre authentication handover in ICN future mobile network.

Ericsson MSLD PAKISTAN PVT LTD. (Packet core BO engineer LTE) november 2014 Jan 2016

- operation and maintenance of Warid 4G LTE project Packet core
- Performance optimization and Operation of Packet Core Nodes -SGSN, GGSN, MME, SGW, PGW.
- Hands on experience on Cisco ASR 5x00 used as SGSN/MME, GGSN/SPGW
- Planning and configuration of Packet Core Nodes-GGSN, AAA, DNS. etc
- Installation and commissioning of Cisco ASR 5000

Salam Mobile ApS Denmark (Project engineer) from march 2014 to November 2014.

- Design, implementation, ongoing management and troubleshooting of Porta One class five switch, including Call Manager / Unified messaging.
- Implementation of all services for Salam cellular company regarding Porta One. e.g. Auto Attendant, call routing, tariff management, Access List Configuration, Media Resource Configuration, Music On Hold Audio Source Configuration, Music On Hold Server Configuration, Device Configuration, Gateway Configuration, Phone Configuration and Trunk Configuration.
- Configuration of call signaling protocols on Voice Gateways H.323 ,MGCP and SCCP

Gurucom Inc. THE VOIP FACTORY United States Amaerica (VOIP Engineer) 2013

- Complete configuration and integration on VSC and VOS soft switches of different versions.
- Managing full project of gurupinless on wholesale and retail basis.
- Managing trunk and vpn services provided.

BLUE STORM ELECTROMECHANICAL PROJECTS & MAINTENANCE UNITED ARAB EMIRATES: Network Communication Engineer(2011)

- Managing all Datacom Maintenance Project.
- Monitoring the network.
- Configured and maintained networking devices on the LAN, WAN, CISCO routers, Switches, Wireless (Cyclone, Orthagon, Canopyetc.)
- Implementation of TCP/IP & related Services-DHCP.
- Trouble shooting and problem resolution of exclusive customer network difficulties.
- Configure and implement Remote Access Solution: VPN.
- MPLS VPN/MVPN testing.
- Version Up gradation and replacement of faulty boards of the routers.

- Working on the technologies like BGP, MPLS TE, MPLS/L2VPN, MPLS/L3VPN, MVPN, Multicasting, OSPF, IP-Trunk, Eth-trunk.
- Evaluation of new network technologies, management, and analytical tools.
- Perform Troubleshooting end-to-end between the several sites.
- Working as a SITE INCHARGE in a In Building Solutions IBS projects.
- Design the layout for cable Installations.
- Works in Network Operation Centre for a vendor Leblanc telecom L.L.C U.A.E.
- Installation of complete site In Building Solution.
- Testing and commissioning.

ELECTRONIC TRADERS PAKISTAN (OUT SOURCE MOBILINK EMPLOYEE): Communication (BSS& NSS) Engineer (2008 to 2010)

- O&M of Microwave links of different vendors (NEC, Dragon Wave) involving troubleshooting hardware replacement and configuration.
- Done the PM and CM of sites.
- Microwave network analysis and audit.
- O&M of NEC Microwave Links by using PNMT & HyperTerminal.
- Rectification of Core Network connectivity.
- Conducted surveys for LOS
- Maintain Sites Connectivity.

COMPUTER SKILLS & EXPERTISE:

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Cisco 2600 Series Router
- Cisco 2800 Series Router
- Cisco 1841 routers
- Cisco WS-C2960-24TT-L switch
- Catalyst 3560-24PS switch
- Other Cisco switches (such as a 2950 or 3550 and same series)
- Routing Protocols (BGP, MBGP, IS-IS, OSPF, EIGRP and RIP)
- MPLS (TDP & LDP) and MPLS TE (RSVP)
- MPLS VPNs, IP Sec VPNs and L2VPN using MPLS.
- Layer 3 Multicasting
- QOS implementation for different types of traffic (Voice, Signaling, Charging and O&M)
- <u>Layer 2 protocols and technologies (Frame Relay, Ethernet, PPP and PPPoE).</u>

- <u>Network Redundancy VRRP, HSRP e.g.</u>
- Good knowledge of Digital Telephony.
- Have strong concepts of GSM and GPRS Network.
- Working experience and good command on Engineering Tools like MATLAB and SIMULINK.
- Good understanding of Microsoft Office Tools like MS word, Power point and Excel.
- A fair ability to interact with any kind of Computer Software.

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- Have good Communication Skills and Team Work.
- Have good Presentation Skills.

FINAL YEAR PROJECT/THESIS:

In press "ICN-based Authentication Protocol for a Simplified LTE Architecture" In EEE International Conference on Communications21-25 May 2017 // Paris // France.

My thesis of master's degree in Halmstad university Sweden was on INVESTIGATE **SOLUTIONS FOR INTRUSION PREVENTION AND DETECTION**. It was a practical based project thesis, which investigates different solutions of network security by combining IPS and IDS.

My Final Year Project in Bachelors was **"USE OF ADAPTIVE BEAMFORMING TO INCREASE THE CAPACITY OF CDMA NETWORKS"**. It was a research based project and was based on studying beam forming algorithms and by them applying smart antennas on CDMA network to increase its capacity.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Date of Birth: 1986	5 th March,	Marital Status:Domicile:	Single Punjab	
ResidencePersonal no.Nationality:	Italy 9860305-4967 Pakistani	Domicile.	ruijab	

REFERENCES:

Omair Khan

CEO Salam Mobile Aps denmark.

Mobile 004520717786

Email:- ok@zap-itsolutions.com

Olga Torstensson

Lecturer , Cisco Networking Academy Program Mob 0046738191724 Work 004635-167575

Email:- olga.torstensson@hh.se

Umair Aslam

Designer software, Ericsson AB Stockholm Sweden. Mob 0046722449844 Work 0046107139844

Email: <u>umair.aslam@ericsson.com</u>

Sohail Murtaza

Technical user Support Analyst, Medtronic Danmark A/S Work (+45) 32 48 18 00 Mobile (+45) 27 53 82 05

Email: sohail.murtaza@medtronic.com

John Graffmann

IT Manager, Medtronic Danmark A/S Work (+45) 32481800 Direct(+45) 32481842 Mobile(+45) 27538203

Zahir Alli

Customer Solutions Consultant, Cryptzone Sweden Email: zahir.alsaab@gmail.com